# Ruby (Sattar) Romeu - Full Stack Engineer

Yes, Ruby, like the programming language.

I'm an engineer in the Greater Boston Area who has built multiple full-stack applications. Using software development as well as my background in education, my goal is to impact educational technology and the future of tech resources available in underserved communities.



rubysattar@gmail.com

#### **SOFTWARE EXPERIENCE**

## General Assembly, Boston - Engineering Fellow JUNE 2020 - SEP 2020

At GA's Software Engineering Immersive program, I received a holistic technical foundation essential for full-stack development.

- Built full-stack applications for teachers and currently conducting user research for continued iteration.
- Incorporated functionality from 3rd-party APIs to add complexity and nuance.
- Collaborated on teams to build and demo applications in an Agile workflow.
- Problem-solved using industry standard development tools and documentation.

#### **STEM ENRG, Boston - Engineering Mentee** SEP 2020 - PRESENT

A 6-month program to create economic equity for women of color in STEM careers where I benefited from mentorship, leadership training, and collaboration in the tech industry.

#### **PROJECTS**

**OverAchiever** — *A flashcard learning application* [Python, Django, React, Javascript, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap, SCSS]

**The Holistic Educator** — *A classroom connections tracking application* [Mongoose, Express, MongoDB, Javascript, Bootstrap, Handlebars, SCSS]

**Education Donation Store**— *E-Commerce Team project/application* [Mongoose, Express, React]S, Javascript, Bootstrap, SCSS]

#### OTHER PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **KIPP Academy, Boston - Lead Teacher FEB 2018 - JUNE 2020**

KIPP is a mission-driven school where teachers regularly collaborate.

- Led a DEI workshop for a team of 30+ educators and school leaders, resulting in actionable commitments for the school environment
- Designed a K-8 Women's History curriculum with G-Suite tech resources.
- Utilized Tableau to analyze data and inform instruction

The Mildred (BPS), Boston - Lead Teacher OCT 2017 - FEB 2018

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

Javascript MongoDB
React NoSQL
jQuery Node.js
Mongoose Express.js
CSS/Scss Bootstrap
Django SQL
RESTful API's

# SKILLS

Cross-industry technology Teamwork Leadership Trouble-shooting Communication

#### **EDUCATION**

Coaching

### LinkedIn Learning — Certificates

NOV 2019

HTML, CSS, SCRUM

# Florida International University, Miami — Bachelor's in Elementary Education

MAY 2012 - DECEMBER 2014

Magna Cum Laude, Honors,
field research in ed-tech.

SFPCC of Harvard, Boston - Lead Teacher AUG 2015 - MAY 2017